A Guide to the Richmond (Va.) Dept. of Community Development, Real Estate Appraisals, Jackson Ward, Richmond, Virginia, ca. 1966
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Richmond (Va.) Dept. of Community Development, Real Estate Appraisals, Jackson Ward, Richmond, Virginia, ca. 1966
The Library of Virginia
42637
.5 cu. ft.
Richmond (Va.) Dept. of Community Development
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by the Richmond (Va.) Dept. of Community Development, Richmond, Virginia, 18 April 2006.
Scope and Content
This accession consists of twenty-nine real estate appraisal reports for the Jackson Ward neighborhood of Richmond, Virginia, circa 1966. Pleasant H. Bagby, M.A.I., real estate appraiser and consultant, conducted the appraisals. The exact impetus for these appraisals is not known, but it appears that it was in preparation for the construction of the Richmond Coliseum. It is evident from the parcel numbering system that several gaps exist in the documentation.
The appraisals include the property owner's name, a legal description of the property, assessment, neighborhood data, delineation of the title, site data, zoning, highest and best use, overall site value, subject site value, improvement data, valuation approaches (market data, income, and cost), final value estimate, certification of the appraiser, qualifications of the appraiser, photographs, and plat maps.
Arrangement
Arranged numerically by parcel number.
Contents List
- Sales brochure for Coliseum 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Parcel 1, 527 N. 5th St., Henry W. Woody Estate ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Parcel 9, 519 N. 5th St., Mendel and Gertrude Schiff ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Parcel 10, Rear 519 N. 5th St., Benjamin L. and Julia E. Bass ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Parcel 12, 513 and 515 N. 5th St., Alexander A. Hector Estate ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Parcel 14, 511 N. 5th St., Rosa B. Arvin (Life) ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Parcel 15, 509-1/2 N. 5th St., Ellis T. Bailey ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Parcel 16, 507, 507-1/2, and 509 N. 5th St., Albert and Carroll B. Wilkins ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Parcel 18, 500 E. Clay St., Eliza Catarsi ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Parcel 19, 504 E. Clay St., Lucy E. Taylor ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Parcel 21, 508 and 508-1/2 E. Clay St., Willis L. and Bertha Lonzer ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Parcel 23, 514-1/2 N. 6th St., Philip N. Brauer ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Parcel 24, 514 N. 6th St., William B., Jr., and Mary P. Pleasants ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Parcel 25, 500 Block N. 6th St., Charles and Isadore J. Siegel ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Parcel 26, 506-1/2 N. 6th St., F. W., Jr., and Herman C. Brauer Estates ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Parcel 27, 506 N. 6th St., F. W. Brauer, Jr. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Parcel 28, 504 N. 6th St., William Pleasants, Jr. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Parcel 29, 500 Block N. 6th St., Bailey E. and Alma P. Creps ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Parcel 31, S/E Corner 6th and Leigh Sts., Harold V. Groome ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Parcel 33, 600 Block E. Leigh St., John W. Pearsall ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Parcel 34, 500 Block N. 7th St., Harold V. Groome ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Parcel 35, 515 N. 6th St., Douglas Finance Corp. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Parcel 36, 514-1/2 N. 7th St., Charles Siegel ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Parcel 38, 513 N. 6th St., Wil-Dav Corp. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Parcel 39, 514 N. 7th St., Wil-Dav Corp. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Parcel 40, 511 N. 6th St., Mathew and Anna Grooms ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Parcel 41, 507-1/2 and 509 N. 6th St., Russell Crawford ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Parcel 42, 512 N. 7th St., George A. Hase ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Parcel 43, 507 N. 6th St., Charles L. Green. ca. 1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)